# Ripudaman Singh

# Software Developer

**Address** Gwalior, India 474005

**Phone** 7000934949

**E-mail** ripudamantheofficial@gmail.com

**LinkedIn** https://linkedin.com/in/rds0751

WWW https://zety.com/profile/ripudaman-

singh/301

Adaptable Blockchain Engineer combines deep technical knowledge with creative design philosophies to develop advanced solutions. Focuses on risk-based security assessments and control matrix reviews. Steady provider of advancement in blockchain application range and concentrations. Experienced blockchain developer with over 2 years of experience in software industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

## **Technical Profile**

- Python
- JavaScript
- Git
- Artificial Intelligence
- React.js
- React Native
- SQL
- PostgreSQL
- Solidity
- Rust

# **Competencies**

Active Listening

Critical Thinking

**Decision-Making** 

Organization and Time Management

Planning and Coordination

## **Work History**

2022-01 - 2022-07

## **Blockchain Developer**

Blockfinch Technologies Private Limited, Gurgaon

- Collaborated with engineering team to review application requirements, plan implementation details and estimate delivery timelines.
- Wrote technical documentation to communicate key points to stakeholders.

- Built stable and secure systems to translate dense technical topics to stakeholders less versed with blockchain applications.
- Led, built and owned backend services and infrastructure to power core blockchain-based products.
- Build bridge to connect two blockchain networks, also a swap.

#### 2019-11 - 2021-12

## Software Developer Team Lead

Dibort Market Ltd., United Kingdom, Remote Patiala

- Held cross-disciplinary brainstorming sessions with technical leads from forex and crypto market.
- Created long-term development plans to optimize performance within multiproject and multi-team environments.
- Solicited aid from inter-departmental personnel and third-party contractors during complex projects.
- Recruited technical subject matter experts to plan and monitor software development teams through phases of project completion.
- Analyzed work to generate logic for new systems, procedures and tests.
- gained experience on ERC20, ERC721 and other crypto products.

#### 2018-07 - 2019-08

#### **Technical Lead**

ApproApp, New Delhi

- My own startup, product was Blockchain based Dynamic ERP system, was used by Thapar University & Rajasthan Technical University.
- Advised management, business and technical staff on solutions using specific domains or technology.
- Drove technical initiatives for large enterprise systems to align with long-term business strategies.
- Offered input on technical and platform-related strategic planning initiatives.
- Guided teams during continuous integration / continuous delivery (CI/CD) processes.

#### https://github.com/ApproApp/ApproApp

#### 2017-02 - 2018-07

## **Software Developer**

Wilqo Media Private Limited, Patiala

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Designed reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments.
- Led version control efforts for organization, employing public and open source repositories.

#### 2017-01 - 2017-08

# Software Developer Team Lead

Wosumo Optimized Marketing, Patiala

• Created long-term development plans to optimize performance within multiproject and multi-team environments.

- Solicited aid from inter-departmental personnel and third-party contractors during complex projects.
- Recruited technical subject matter experts to plan and monitor software development teams through phases of project completion.

# **Accomplishments**

- Resolved the upgradeable contracts issue on a different blockchain network that was not supporting it yet.
- Supervised team of 5 college students create a blockchain based service.
- Designed and implemented ApproApp the decentralized dynamic ERP system.

### **Education**

2011-07 - 2013-07 **Secondary School** 

Kendriya Vidyalaya - Gwalior

2014-07 - 2016-05 Senior School: Science Education

Kendriya Vidyalaya - Gwalior

2016-07 - Current Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

Thapar Institute of Engineering & Technology - Patiala